Marc Labelle

SDET & Validation Manager

SUMMARY

Exceptional and deep experience in the technology industry, from Fortune 50 semiconductor manufacturers to startups. Over 25 years of experience with automation, process documentation, and leadership. Looking to join a team as an individual contributor or manager where I can use my body of experience to build or upskill an existing team.

TECHNOLOGIES

Programming Languages: C/C++, Java, C#, Rust, Perl, Bash, CMAKE, JavaScript, SQL

Source Control: Git, ClearCase, SVN, Perforce

Frameworks: Selenium, Appium, Ranorex, Cucumber (Gherkin), Postman, Custom SOAP

Documentation: Testrail, Jira, Confluence, ClearQuest, QualityCenter

Infrastructure: Docker, Jenkins, GitLab CI, CI/CD Pipelines, TDD/BDD, iOS & Android SDK

RELEVANT SKILLS

- Management and team development:
 - o Experience with multiple process management styles including MBOs and OKRs.
 - Learning & development materials focused on upskilling team members.
 - o Build loyal and driven teams that push limits and produce results.
 - Excellent process building using collaborative approaches with stakeholders.
 - o Relationship building between Product, Engineering, & QA teams.
- Information Security:
 - Focused penetration testing and hardening systems against attack.
 - Written two bespoke fuzzers, implemented commercial fuzzer products.
 - Markov chain generators for probability based actions.
- User focused design.
- Excellent documentation and demonstration skills, from total beginner to expert in the field.

EXPERIENCE

QA Manager, Payward Inc DBA Kraken

Remote — Feb 2018 - Jan 2023

Primary focus was the leadership of the QA team, guidance to the broader team, and mentorship to QA Leads. Built organizational level programs focused on broad impacts; on-call policy and rotas.

Accomplishments

- Joined as 1 of only 2 QA, bootstrapped the entire QA process for the front end team.
- Developed and maintained over 1300 unique test cases for regression and feature testing.
- Took leadership of the QA team acting as QA Director through the hyper growth of 9 to 84 members.
- Created a highly collaborative work environment between QA and Development.
- Greatly reduced downtime (by 2 orders of magnitude) through improved QA process and deployment process.

Marc Labelle

SDET & Validation Manager

QA Analyst, Escape Technology Corp

Roseville, CA — Jun 2016 - Feb 2018

Primary focus was the validation of our product: Online 5. Acted in a backup capacity to finance support team. Handled more technical questions, assisted in root causing potential bugs and wrote one-off SQL queries to better delve into customer issues.

Accomplishments

- Created an automation suite using the Ranorex test framework to perform continuous regression tests.
- Acted in the role of lead QA/validation for the finance portion of the product.
- Documented errata, coordinated with technical writer to clearly communicate said errata in documentation platform.

Validation and Debug Engineer, Intel Corp

Folsom, CA — Feb 1999 - Jun 2016

Having worked at Intel for 17 years I have covered a diverse spectrum of positions. Overall focus has always been on validation, testing and documenting procedures for juniors. Direct experience in Communications Silicon, NOR Flash, and Chipset Firmware.

Accomplishments

- Multiple awards for operational excellence and quality.
- Produced several hundred documents on how to execute procedures.
- Implemented and executed training to junior positions from around the world.
- Developed and maintained several code projects, each several thousand to several million lines of code.

EDUCATION

Stanford & Massachusetts Institute of Technology, OpenCourseware, online

Making extensive use of the OpenCourseware program from both institutions for personal/professional education.

Sierra College, Rocklin CA

Completed an associate's degree program. Focus on Computer Science and Technology.

AWARDS and INTERESTS

- Recognised for public speaking by Toastmasters.
- Awards for community service from Optimist International.
- Award for completion of instructor training for martial arts.
- Second degree black belt and enjoyed teaching children martial arts and self discipline.